

#### **PROFILE**

I bring a vast knowledge base, from a wide range of experiences, to add value to my clients' in ways that consistently exceed expectations. I communication skills, with analytical skills, and leadership to contribute to my teams success. I have demonstrated good acumen in developing and leading with successful ventures in both.

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication ( Public Speaking Innovative Teamwork C++ Python SOL Adobe Suite MS Office

## **INFO**



# **Address**

Brampton, ON Canada



#### **Phone**

(226) 980-5036



#### **Email**



#### Website



#### Github

github.com/rheera

# RAMAN HEERA

# **DEVELOPER**



#### WORK EXPERIENCE



#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN | ROBARTS RESEARCH INST. 2017-2018**

- Worked on creating a Slicer module capable of replicating X-ray results, for surgeons to practice virtual spinal interventions, without using fluoroscopy.
- Eliminates the exposure to radiation during training.
- Uses an optical tracker to capture the spine model, the needle, and the virtual fluoroscope camera head in 3D space with minimal input lag.
- Created in-depth documentation for future developers to work on the project as well as for anyone looking to use it.
- Created the module using CPP within Visual Studio.

#### CO-FOUNDER | DAPPER BLVD. 2015-2019

- Co-founded a men's accessory e-commerce boutique.
- Responsible for marketing, such as making sure the website and social media is aesthetically pleasing and running smoothly.
- Also delegated tasks, filling all roles myself when needed, such as: ordering products in bulk, innovating designs, assembling merchandise, establishing and maintaining customer relations.
- Effective written and oral communication with partners and clients.



# **EDUCATION**



Dean's Honour List

# London, ON | April 2018 UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN ONTARIO

**B.Sc IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** MINOR IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING



#### **CERTIFCATIONS**



**CLOUD PRACTITIONER | AMAZON WEB SERVICES. 2019-2022** 



## **PROJECTS**



# TEAM LEAD | NVIZION. 2016-2017

- Collaboration Project with Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry
- Completely updated and revamped an employee organization system for Schulich.
- Added visualization features such as graphs and sorting methods for quick reduction in data.
- Created a lucid install and user guide; as well as a detailed report with all features, deliverables, design patterns, and use cases.
- Created using CPP.

# **DEVELOPER** | NBA Stats to Redefine Player Roles. 2018

- Created a script using Selenium in Python to scrape data from a Basketball Reference website and input the data into an SQL database
- Used the data to weigh different statistics and create new positions, rather than just the traditional five positions.
- Using these positions and stats we could find better team compositions.
- Created using Python and SQL